a very important stock that making news
flow since yesterday evening that's
lakmi vas Bank Shakti sinna director at
lxmi vas bank is now with us shaki
thanks so much for taking our time for
us the news flow doesn't really seem to
be good there is a moratorium of one
month uh then a draft merger scheme with
DBS can you talk to us and address the
concerns that a lot of clients of lxmi
vas bank will be having at this moment
also a lot of
stakeholders M absolutely thank you for
uh giving this chance you know uh this
did come as a surprise to us though the
bank is in trouble has been in trouble
for some time now things has started
improving slowly our recoveries had
improved our depositors have started
coming back at this moment for one the
bank is flushed with liquidity our
liquidity coverage ratio at 240% as
against the requirement of 100% so I
think the moratorium on the withdrawal I
think is possibly an overreaction and
the fact that you know board had there
was a coup in the bank in one sense
where the shareholders threw out the
existing board almost completely and
then for about a month we saw
withdrawals of 2,000 crores that
deposited fell down almost a run
subsequent three weeks we have recovered
more than half of it but for the volum
have been better so depositors have
started coming back with the bank they
felt fine this bank will pull through it
will pull through I know but at this
moment by moratorium would obviously
upset the depositors particularly those
who have come back have done the right
thing and number two in this kind of
amalgamation where you're completely
extinguishing all shares major
shareholders will find the way to El
take it whatever they'll have their
Solutions what we were more worried
about when we were negotiating with
colle for the merger earlier was what
does one do with the smallest
shareholders the retail shareholders
does one should we not give them some
amount of care for them and I think with
this these two categories of people the
depositors and the smaller shareholders
would definitely have a lot of concern
even though let me assure you DBS is an
outstanding bank it'll bring a lot of
cash it'll really be good for the system
but immediately these two tensions I see
coming
up right when you talk about you know
the bank has healthy liquidity but
despite that you saw some withdrawals or
run of deposit of around, 1500 2,000
crores what was the immediate
fundraising requirement because of which
this moratorium probably came
in uh we were looking at raising 2,000
CR Plus
at least 1,500 crores immediately 500
through a rights issue which will give
us but ultimately 2,500 is possibly the
right number to make the bank not only
liquid in the sense of attaining his
Capital adequacy ratio of
8.875 but also allowing the bank to then
resume operations because of the
preventive correct action PCA order of
September last year the bank's loan
books has been shrinking from 21,000
cres it has fallen to under 14,000 cres
but to survive you have to come back on
the growth path that would come once you
satisfy your adequacy requirements and
have something left over to then grow
your business so I think the DBS money
of 2500 CR would allow the bank the
network atast the bank would survive but
the existing Network would then recover
and take off with them that's the kind
of figure we're looking at
25 uh Mr s just want to understand as
well what's in it for the shareholders
because if the company or the bank
rather has eroded the net worth then
shareholders um stand to lose out can
you just clarify here see Tech you're
very good question technically once we
net worth is negative our Capital ratio
is minus 2.85 technically today there is
no value to the share right that's only
technicality it has no value fine but
the market was placing it at 15 rupees
and with a recovery plan it would have
gone back again to the higher levels of
before so in that sense yes as of the
shares had no value but no the shares
have an inherent value the bank is an
old bank it has a very good uh liability
franchise going for it so I think
there's a lot going for it but yes with
this new order effectively it amounts to
wiping out the entire share Capital the
premium the surpluses everything then
becomes zero so the existing
shareholders are today at level of zero
everything is wiped out that is the
point
okay um can you just also give us a
sense as to what the Outlook is going to
be in terms of what the process is now
this moratorium period after it gets
over how exactly it's going to work what
the financial ratios could potentially
look like as
well uh very quickly before that you
know we were given charges this Bank end
of September in 52 days we saw that our
recoveries NPA recoveries from NPA and
to upgradation had already hit 50 cres
and we had sorted out one time
settlements of 150 crores plus so we
would see at least 200 crores plus
coming back which would right back into
the capital so in that sense already we
were on that track now with the
moratorium it gives a shock temporarily
but I guess the uh new administrator and
the RBI would realize that borium
possibly is not required hopefully they
would scale it down and allow depositors
to operate their accounts normally and
then with the merger process is a very
difficult process the bank as I said
inherently liquid but yes it doesn't
have the Reserves it capital adequacy
ratio is negative so with that money
coming in it'll enable the bank to
attain the level of as I said minimum of
8.875 as soon as the money starts
flowing in from DBS but the process I
think is not likely to take anything
less than 6 months so adequate
provisioning is there as I said we're
very comfortable in in all those S A
provisioning is at 80% ear it was 70% 6
months ago now 80% so all those ratios
are very comfortable as the bank is
concerned it was stuck times to the
legacy of npas and that was really
pulling it down you
know and The NPS also come down in the
in the three months it has come down
from 25.4% to
24.5% which is not insignificant so I
think it'll be going forward I would be
very confident that the system would
really come back to normaly very soon
right I mean 24 is still pretty high sir
despite it coming off 1% but anyways you
know talking about the future now
moratorium has been placed for the next
one month there are some limits DBS as a
you know banking partner or you know a
parent comes into the company what do
they bring on the table they are not a
small brand they're not a brand which is
investing less money what does it bring
on the table for the bank what does
2,500 CR do and what does the 560
branches of lbb do for the combined
uh let's start with the last lbb we
reduced five branches I think anybody
who takes over the branch we have a very
good look at it at least 200 branches
are today running at a loss some of them
may recover in the next couple of years
some will not recover so when you look
at the branch if you look at the
business per employee Which is less than
say 5 four five I think those branches
would have to be shut down Amal
whichever word you want to use wherever
there are redundancies where the BBS
India is already there then obviously
they would again relook at amalgamation
to reduce amalgamation is always a very
awkward thing because your systems are
very different the human resource
systems are different organograms are
different internal processes are
different so it is going to take some
time for this 2,500 to really
materialize and Sh up the capital as I
said all the branch Bank requires today
is to show up a capital and to
progressively rationalize its operations
to cut the operating cost so n interest
margin has to come back to decent levels
otherwise how does the bank operate it
can't just operate by a onetime infusion
of capital it has to inherently be
solvent by itself and that will come for
dazation of expenditures which are have
been coming down considerably in the
last one year but are still much higher
than what you would expect for a normal
bank so it will be painful for some
employees it will be painful for some
employees absolutely
right thank you so much sir for taking
our time for us all the best for the
future of course it's an important
development when you talk about the
banking sector let's get some
perspective from none other than Tamal
badya uh he's been tracking banks for
now ages Tamal thanks so much uh for
taking our time for us you know time and
again it was yes bank first then it was
a Maharashtra based PMC Bank uh and now
lbb uh you know put under moratorium
what is the sense that you get you know
with these Banks especially the smaller
ones what is the telling
us no uh you know there's no surprise
that lbv has been sick a ster case uh
even though the management can claim
that things have been getting better and
all uh but all of us
um knew this for quite some time that
things are not okay and it has to be
done it needs to be solved I think
Reserve Bank of India was uh looking for
a market Le solution which has all along
been the case even for years Bank also
and if you remember last year one large
nbfc which
is uh applied I mean announced the
marger with itself and uh and Reserve
Bank of India took a long time um and
finally it said no because it was almost
getting a new giving a new license and I
don't know whether RBI had reservations
about an nvfc getting into banking uh
but in the past it had happened or um
that particular entity did not suit the
fit and proper criteria so that has been
the case and it has been going on and
what the announcement what happened
yesterday I think it was in the meting
for long uh on the one hand Reserve Bank
of India Works in I mean this with the
DBS the discussions were on if if my
source is correct and on the other hand
the current management was was um
looking for a market Le solution getting
some investors but the key problem which
not too many of us are discussing is
this this is a classic case of the
promoters which should not be running
the banks I hate to use the word rogue
promoters but probably some of the
promoters they are not holding large U
Stakes but they were using the bank the
way nobody should should have been done
so if you look at the MAA case unlike
yes Bank yes Bank case is a moratorium
this also moratorium in that sense both
of them have taken the same route but an
yesbank case was a reconstruction
meaning yes Bank remains as yes Bank it
will be reconstructed and they found a
way of what has to be done but in this
case is a marger marger with another
entity and because its network is
negative all the existing shareholders
do not get anything so I think it's a
big lesson big slap on the face of the
promoters who do not run the bank the
way a bank should be run so they deserve
to be left on the street they should not
get anything out of it so I think what
we are seeing now Reserve Bank of India
is now experimenting a new our ways we
have found that yes Bank I'm not getting
to PMC because that was not a k much
that was a cooperative bank but in the
main Commercial Banking space the
traditionally what used to be happened
RBI would look for a suitter and then
then you know it would it would work out
at a background deal something like that
but this is no more happening yes Bank
was a very different kind of case and
this also is a very different kind of
case and I have seen newspaper repor
talking about that DBS has come to the
rescue of uh of lakmi vas Bank RBI has
used that I I they to differ I think
it's a wi it's it's a for DBS it's it's
an opportunity to grow in India which it
has been planning to do and it's we
can't call it a foreign bank because
it's not a branch of DBS Singapore it's
a locally Incorporated bank which has
been planning to go in a big way in the
retail segment it is uh it is about two
dozen plus cities it has been present
Etc and now overnight it gets 560
branches predominantly in in southern
part of the country I think 85% in
southern part of the country and
probably 50% is Tamil NAD or somewhere
else so it's not a DBS has come as a
white night it also helps DBS uh to
increase its footprint and to to realize
his dream of uh going big retail in one
of the largest markets globally because
Indian market is something huge
opportunities so I think it's it's a big
opportunity for DBS let's not look at it
that DBS is being you know forced to
pick it up and you know grudgingly doing
this no I'm sure DBS has been very keen
and the discussion has been on for long
so the only loser in this case
depositors will get their money uh lbb
will grow uh the only losers are the
promoters of this Bank those who have
been you know not running the bank the
way a bank should be run though were
those who are not caring for the dep
money they're just using the bank as a
vehicle to make their to fulfill their
own purposes and they have been taught a
lessons
sure right Mr bandad we'll let you go on
that note thank you so much for taking
time out and giving us your Viewpoint as
to how you've looked at this latest news
with respect to
lvb uh and the merger with DBS as well
as the steps that the RBI has taken